<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tom Mault</title>
    <description>Third Year Geography and Management Student. Works in IT Support.</description>
    <link>http://tmault.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tmault.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Technological Bypass</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Problem: There’s a HDMI cable running between my laptop and living room tv whenever I want to stream movies or shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s plenty of options available, but there’s two that seem interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution 1: Some form of wireless broadcasting from my laptop to the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution 2: Controlling a cheap device connected to my tv that can stream directly from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution 1 probably involves messing around with Codecs, Drivers, Streaming, Compression, Encryption and Networking. All complex stuff. Solution 2 needs a little piece of standard hardware, running a small server function to communicate with the internet and local devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which of these has a bigger research cost to prototype and develop? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moore’s Law is compacting our devices, down to the point that streaming 1080P and beyond can be handled by a fanless chip on a stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a whole new encoding method, drivers and hardware to wirelessly use a television as a second screen for a laptop is a whole different beast. There’s so many limits to fight. First of all, the local network is streaming high quality content to the users laptop. Then, you’re trying to relay that content from the laptop, back to the router and into the fancy piece of kit plugged in to the tv. This is a nightmare for I/O and bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s much simpler to have the laptop tell the chip on a stick (a) what video stream and (b) when to do it. That’s lightweight. Much simpler, much less intensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something intriguing about a chip on a stick (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.uk/chrome/devices/chromecast/&quot;&gt;ChromeCast&lt;/a&gt;) bypassing problems that are complicated (&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtame.com/&quot;&gt;Check out Airtime&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this comes from using a process like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5_Whys&quot;&gt;5 Why’s&lt;/a&gt; to figure out what pain point you’re actually trying to solve. Don’t take the first-order why. Figure what you’re actually trying to do. &lt;em&gt;I.e. Control a big screen from the comfort of your sofa&lt;/em&gt;. This is not the same task as &lt;em&gt;develop the capability to mount your television as a second monitor&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on the use cases you’re solving - because the problems that you can technologically bypass are limited by the needs of said group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 13:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/techbypass/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/techbypass/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smart Things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you buy twenty pairs of identical socks, you’ll never have to pair socks again. For the rest of your life. Never. Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s probably not a good idea to buy that ‘premium’ (loud) polo shirt. Or to pay through the roof for a little emblem on your chest. Nobody ever knocked well fitting clothes in solid colours. They minimise the chance of looking silly in photos a decade from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backup your computer off-site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you buy something worth more than £400, you should probably check it will be covered by your contents/possessions insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watermark and redact information from ID scans before you send them off to third parties. If they are plastered with the date and purpose of identification, they’re going to be of limited use if they fall into the wrong hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t use things that aren’t fit for purpose. Don’t use things when your interests don’t align with the vendor. E.g. Backups: pay per GB and use a backup-specific service - not generic (consumer) cloud storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a list of the applications that you use on your computer. This way, &lt;del&gt;if&lt;/del&gt; &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; your computer breaks, you will be able to get back up to speed much quicker. Update this file every time you install a new program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use open file formats. Don’t use proprietary things, because ten years from now, you’ll be somewhere between very sad and inhospitably angry at your past self when you can’t get at a given file. Using stuff like .txt and .md also tends to be a bit more lightweight, which reduces your digital overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your laundry when the basket is two thirds full. It’s way less stressful when you just have to pop one load in. It beats the alternative of letting it pile up until you run out of clothes and &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to do it, which suddenly has dwarfed into a task that takes all day. Do it on the fly, do it before you need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That person that inspires you? They’re human too. Thanks to Twitter, Meerkat and Email, they’re way more reachable than you think. Be genuine and the world unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 13:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/smart/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/smart/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Principles of Good Business Process Management (Brocke et al., 2014)</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-context-awareness&quot;&gt;Principle of Context Awareness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM can’t follow a cookbook approach - it must fit to the specific organisational context.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cookbook approaches lead to project failures.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What context? Organisational size, strategy, industry, make, objectives and available resources etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-continuity&quot;&gt;Principle of Continuity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM should be a permanent practice, not just a one-off project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM isn’t about quick wins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hammer (2010) established that isolated projects (both incremental and radical) can only lead to temporary competitive advantage, as the economic environment and competition will continue to evolve. BPM must become a part of organisational culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-enablement&quot;&gt;Principle of Enablement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM isn’t about firefighting or heroic recovery from failures. It’s about uncovering and developing capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM is about building the capabilities needed by an organisation now and in the future (Teece, 2009).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-holism&quot;&gt;Principle of Holism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM shouldn’t be isolated to specific areas of the organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The choice of IT systems should not merely meet the local requirements of one function, but rather fit the organisations needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-institutionalisation&quot;&gt;Principle of Institutionalisation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM needs to become part of the organisational structure. It isn’t an after-thought or ad-hoc responsibility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entrenched habits and adverse circumstances promote silo behaviour, which thwarts the development of horizontal processes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formalising roles and responsibilities for BPM helps ensure the organisation is rebalanced in favour of &lt;strong&gt;customer-centric, horizontal integration of work&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-involvement&quot;&gt;Principle of Involvement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All stakeholders should be integrated into BPM. The employees certainly shouldn’t be neglected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organisational changes can be very threatening and often trigger employee resistance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple methods, like employee idea boxes and collaborative process modelling can create a sense of involvement, commitment and ownership amongst staff, reducing the amount of resistance changes face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-joint-understanding&quot;&gt;Principle of Joint Understanding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM shouldn’t be undertaken solely by experts, in expert language.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM is a mechanism to enable different stakeholders to “view, frame and analyse organisational systems” (Page 537). In order for this to happen, it must be developed using a common, non-domain specific language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-purpose&quot;&gt;Principle of Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM contributes to the creation of strategic value. It isn’t done for the sake of doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-simplicity&quot;&gt;Principle of Simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM outlays (time, effort, money etc.) should be economical. They must not be over-engineered.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every company should look for the simplest way to achieve its BPM-related goals. They should apply Occam’s Razor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principle-of-technology-appropriation&quot;&gt;Principle of Technology Appropriation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BPM should make opportune use of technology. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Countless IT solutions can be used to foster the efficiency and effectiveness of business processes (Page 538).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As such, IT is transformative. But it’s about supporting the organisation and the fulfilment of its objectives. It shouldn’t be department specific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vom Brocke, J., Schmiedel, T., Recker, J., Trkman, P., Mertens, W., &amp;amp; Viaene, S. (2014). Ten Principles of Good Business Process Management. Business Process Management Journal (BPMJ), 20(4), 530-548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uni.li/tabid/285/id/4273.67/default.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link to Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 14:31:19 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/BPM-principles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/BPM-principles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adopting CRM Technology (Xu et al., 2002)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;adopting-crm-technology-xu-yen-lin-and-chou-2002&quot;&gt;Adopting CRM Technology (Xu, Yen, Lin and Chou, 2002)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;context-for-implementing-crm&quot;&gt;Context for Implementing CRM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Deregulation, diversification and globalisation have stimulated a dramatic rise in competition - and these unforgiving marketplace realities have forced companies to switch from a product-centric approach to a customer-centric approach (Page 451). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRM provides systems, but the effective implementation of CRM systems cannot stop there. Whilst systems may support continuous interactions, fast feedback, adaptation and proactivity, they will not become part of regular practice until business processes are formally changed. As such, CRM should be viewed as a corporate strategy. It needs the backing of all employees in the organisation, and is ideally launched as a grass-routes movement - one to which every employee can contribute ideas and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-crm-help&quot;&gt;How Does CRM Help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer satisfaction is enabled, in part, by the effective and timely allocation of the right tools, people and knowledge to the right problems. CRM systems that are inter-departmental and integrate the front and back office will assist in achieving this outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its most basic form CRM integrates sales, customer service and marketing. Up-to-date information and modelling can assist in the creation of effective cross-selling campaigns. A more thorough implementation of CRM will include data from all functions that touch customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The goal is to improve the customer’s experience of how they interact with us, which hopefully, in turn, creates more satisfaction, which yields more loyalty, which, ideally, yields more sales of products and services (Page 442).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;complexities-of-crm&quot;&gt;Complexities of CRM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;technical&quot;&gt;Technical&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analytical function of CRM is often neglected. The return on customer interaction will be maximised when domain-specific analytical applications are deployed on data warehouses filled with high quality data. Only then will the company hold a comprehensive view of their customers on a case by case basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;personnel&quot;&gt;Personnel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweat (2001) notes that senior management must be aware that CRM is a long-term strategy that is unlikely to have an immediate payoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRM is not just a technology. At the very least, it entails a “fundamental shift in the information flow within an enterprise, from quantitative to qualitative data” (Xu &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;, 2002; 446).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emeraldinsight.com/doi/full/10.1108/02635570210445871&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link to Purchase Full Copy of Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 14:31:19 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/adopting-crm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/adopting-crm/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Customer Relationship Management (Bose, 2002)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;key-components-for-it-success&quot;&gt;Key Components for IT Success&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-crm&quot;&gt;What is CRM?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of technology &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; business processes, used in a manner that satisfies the customer in any given interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRM is about acquiring, analysing and using knowledge about customers in order to sell more goods or services and to do so more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long term, a process of continual analysis and refinement of the firms product mix will enhance the lifetime value of the firm to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CRM may involve fundamental process changes within the organisation; simply providing technology is usually inadequate (Page 93)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-we-need-crm&quot;&gt;Why Do We Need CRM?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world has changed. In 1850, it was good enough to produce a product. In 1900, it was about sales. In the 1950s, market(ing) orientation was the predominant mentality. In the new millennium, the prominent force is Customer-Centric Orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;enabled&lt;/em&gt; by technology. Fast, low-cost, networked environments have enabled mass customisation and personalisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berger and Bechwati (2000) summarise this change as a change in view from business as a series of discrete transactions, to the development and maintenance of long-term relationships. The Customers Lifetime Value (CLV) in the guiding principle of this age. There has been a fundamental shift; from managing the market segment, to managing the specific customer, and his or her individual preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;crm-development&quot;&gt;CRM Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRM is deployed just like any other new technology (Planning, research, system analysis, design, construction, implementation, maintenance/documentation and adaptation). However, it’s not very effective if it’s just a change in technology. In order to be effective it requires business processes and ethos’ to change too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wells &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (1999) laid out four key elements for successfully engineered one-to-one interacting IT Systems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify the means of collecting customer information. Where does data flow in to the organisation? Where do customers interact with the company? Where are the contact points? (E.g. tills, websites, phone lines)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Re-design of customer data. First of all, you have to integrate the customer data across the entire firm. No more data silos for each department! Next, you’ll need to expand the customer data profile. Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) Systems will need somewhere to put this new data! Finally you’ll have to integrate legacy systems, usually requiring the use of middleware to bridge the gap. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IT-enabled interaction. There two principal ways for a CRM system to interact with a customer. Either directly (automated) or through an intermediary, such as an employee in a telephone call centre (IT-enabled)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transmission of data &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How will management at all levels use this information to improve the quality of their decisions? (Page 91)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consider-staging-the-project&quot;&gt;Consider Staging The Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These systems don’t have to implemented all at once. It can be useful to modularise them. There’s a host of technologies and infrastructure investments needed to support a CRM system. Typically, you’ll need a data warehouse, data mining capabilities and network upgrades. Certain business may require integrated phone systems (Voice Over Internet Protocol). There’s a lot of expertise and training required to operate such systems, so deploying them sequentially may be more effective in the long-term than radically changing the business overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;note-common-threats-to-the-implementation-of-any-new-system&quot;&gt;Note Common Threats To The Implementation of Any New System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlsson and Walden (2000) characterise these as ‘people problems’, including, but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People not understanding the new systems, and relying on old intuitions and/or experience &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People being frustrated by theories and ethos changes that they do not fully understand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People circumnavigating new systems to skip process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training. It seems bland, but it is vitally important. Without it, the output of CRM systems can be damaging to business productivity. As Feelders &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (2000) noted, “successful data mining projects require the involvement of &lt;strong&gt;expertise in data mining&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;company data&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;subject area concerned&lt;/strong&gt;” - this is reasonably rare and highly valuable combination to come across. Without it, the output of Customer Centric Intelligence (CCI) applications may be wildly misinterpreted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-will-benefit-the-most-from-crm&quot;&gt;Who Will Benefit The Most From CRM?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firms with these characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accumulate lots of data on each customers buying patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Significant customer life value&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low customer churn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;crm-over-the-next-decade&quot;&gt;CRM Over The Next Decade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papazoglou &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (2000) posits that the power play of the next decade will be found in business alliances. Combining data sets across the enterprise value chain should, in theory, benefit all involved parties. Ideally, such alliances will create synergistic benefits to the whole industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration of systems. At the moment, there’s no monopoly or best-practice implementation of CRM system. Indeed, there isn’t such a status for any constituent component. As the decade progresses, de facto standards for data mining, data warehousing etc. will arise. Off the back of this, CRM system will become easier to implement. Reducing the barriers to entry of CRM systems mean more companies will have them. Soon, they will be a threshold for competition - not a source of competitive advantage. Again, Papazoglou’s recommendation to extend CRM systems across business partners combats this erosion of competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bose notes firms my be wary of short-term focus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CRM is an expensive, time-consuming and complex proposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the firms that can satisfy the needs of each particular customer and the firms that are poised to perform successfully and lead the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emeraldinsight.com/doi/full/10.1108/02635570210419636&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link to Purchase Full Copy of Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 14:31:19 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/bose_on_crm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/bose_on_crm/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Taking Doors Off Your House</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve migrated from Wordpress to Jekyll. In fact, I haven’t migrated. I’ve just started again from scratch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running on Jekyll is a little more secure - there are fewer points of entry. Wordpress was a big, bloated behemoth, far too powerful for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using my VPS to serve up a static site, I’m removing several layers of potential failure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress could break. No longer a risk. A plugin could inject malware. No longer a threat. Someone could brute force my administrator login. No longer a threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a static html site, there’s nothing client-side to hack. The only way for a malicious party to change things is to gain entry through the server itself - and that is a threat that comes with hosting anything on the internet, regardless of if you’re running Wordpress on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of thought process I’m going through in my life at the moment. It’s a bit like removing doors on your house that you never use. The house is a little bit more secure without them, but it doesn’t decrease your ability to use your house at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 14:31:19 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/doors/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/doors/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
